[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf3", "question": "Where did Ichabod Crane reside?", "answer": "Sleepy Hollow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5bea5dad637d903c881c", "question": "Which country observes an official Vernal Equinox Day?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa550dc73aa70ea0b70b20", "question": "Hastings, England has a distinct May Day festival which is known as what?", "answer": "Jack in the Green", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3235cfbf195a31e15d73b3", "question": "Which singer was known as \"The Walrus of Love\"?", "answer": "Barry White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4a97f261d1b4d384d5d68a", "question": "If you have dysmorphia what do you hate?", "answer": "A flawed body part", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a958", "question": "Which European country replaced the Pound with the Euro?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3db", "question": "What company introduced the first transistor-based hearing aid?", "answer": "Zenith", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59068023ff9c0647b50a808a", "question": "Which British actor played the role of Spider-Man in the 2016 film \"Captain America: Civil War\"?", "answer": "Tom Holland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74d", "question": "What martial art name means to strike with the feet?", "answer": "Tae kwon do", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a39", "question": "What former \"Little House on the Prairie\" star served two consecutive terms as president of the Screen Actors Guild?", "answer": "Melissa Gilbert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c953", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Draco?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e6", "question": "On what date did the Menendez murders take place?", "answer": "August 20, 1989", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ef", "question": "What two US states have the word \"Mountain\" in their official nicknames?", "answer": "West Virginia and Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65619ae7e414034b5aec0", "question": "What was Atlas famously forced to do by the Greek gods?", "answer": "Hold the Heavens on his shoulders", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d6", "question": "Hyperopia is the scientific name for what eye condition?", "answer": "Farsightedness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3d65ff048f679a45ab4c", "question": "What is a male camel known as?", "answer": "Bull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b905", "question": "The delicacy known as fois gras traditionally comes from what part of the duck or goose?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa57", "question": "Which country has Budapest as its capital?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd4", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"P\"?", "answer": "Papa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e220fe83fe1f2a824b9c", "question": "What happened to the Soviet air force during the opening days of the German invasion?", "answer": "Up to 2000 aircraft were destroyed on the ground", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010cabb0775fa611bce67fe", "question": "Emetophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Vomit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fdb", "question": "The family on the TV show \"Married...with Children\" was named in honor of what wrestler?", "answer": "KIng Kong Bundy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928b", "question": "\"Highlander\" tells the story of which immortal swords-man?", "answer": "Connor MacLeod", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b349", "question": "Who was the first woman to sail single-handed around the world?", "answer": "Naomi James", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbe4a6ce05a3942286eec", "question": "In the film \"Red Dragon\", Francis Dolarhyde is obsessed with the painting of what English poet?", "answer": "William Blake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121a1963c99d48cd169b00", "question": "What kind of nut is used to make marzipan?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59675fb62b59efe0e9417e9a", "question": "What Country music singer had a #1 single with \"You Look Like I Need A Drink\"?", "answer": "Justin Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339477", "question": "Who played the role of David Dunn in the movie \"Unbreakable\"?", "answer": "Bruce Willis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017371f44491cbd7c5a1784", "question": "Which ancient civilization has magical creatures known as Jinn?", "answer": "Persian - Jinn (sometimes spelled \"djinn\") are mythological creatures of fire and air that inspired most modern-day genie stories.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c737", "question": "What does a lepidopterist study or collect?", "answer": "Butterflies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa40edc73aa70ea0b70b0c", "question": "What does the shape of Nepal's flag represent?", "answer": "The Himalayas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdfbe8e003d27d341092bd0", "question": "Why are Amsterdam's buildings so narrow?", "answer": "A tax loophole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c663", "question": "What name is given to the unit of electrical resistance?", "answer": "Ohm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fb087cecf631c2414a13b58", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", who was responsible for the creation of the Night King?", "answer": "The Children of the Forest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa5b473838c5c8a417f2a", "question": "Automatonophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Ventriloquist dummies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb0a17e83c707845b2106", "question": "Which famous retailer started out as a mail-order watch business?", "answer": "Sears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b176", "question": "In what year did the State of California officially join the United States as its 31st state?", "answer": "1850", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba63b874c93a3298b2157", "question": "In the film \"Men In Black 3\", what did Agent K like to eat in order to think better?", "answer": "Pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c51", "question": "Who starred in the lead male role in the 1968 movie \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f59", "question": "What famous clipper ship took its name from Scots words for \"short shirt\" in a Robert Burns poem?", "answer": "The Cutty Sark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c27", "question": "What is the oldest symphony orchestra in the US?", "answer": "New York Philharmonic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937eab508d98002fdd633a7", "question": "Easter Island is part of which South American country?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80a", "question": "Poutine consists of gravy and cheese curds on top of what?", "answer": "French fries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c163", "question": "What airport has the code MME?", "answer": "Durham Tees Valley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde7", "question": "What sport has thirteen players per team in \"league\" rules but fifteen in \"union\" play?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133889b", "question": "Who was shipwrecked for 28 years, 2 months and 19 days?", "answer": "Robinson Crusoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a0a06c0f9723ab15cb36", "question": "What was the inspiration behind a 12-person jury?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles of Jesus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601600fffe83fe1f2a824c5a", "question": "Why did famous Civil War photographer Mathew Brady go broke?", "answer": "No one wanted to remember the war", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca53", "question": "The rate of change of velocity is known as what?", "answer": "Acceleration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049a05cf93664eb1048696", "question": "The Queensland nut is another name for what nut?", "answer": "Macadamia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe528ec1bf59ab7d2e380ff", "question": "What classic school pet is considered a delicacy in Peru?", "answer": "Guinea pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaac87e83c707845b20e1", "question": "How long does a day last on Saturn?", "answer": "Approximately 10.5 hours", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b371061c3f17ccc40c8e1b", "question": "The name \"gastropub\" is derived from what two words?", "answer": "Gastronomy and pub", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6995720565ad31a57c744", "question": "What name did Jacques Cousteau call his main research vessel?", "answer": "Calypso", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e1", "question": "What river separates Maryland and Virginia?", "answer": "Potomac River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948a", "question": "Which actress played the role of Amelie in the 2001 movie \"Amelie\"?", "answer": "Audrey Tautou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3f11c73aa70ea0b70afb", "question": "Which Italian region is the source of Marsala wine?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af256b3b63e5727cf5a483f", "question": "What popular toy, that is still widely used today, was invented by Arthur K. Melin in 1958?", "answer": "The Hula Hoop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae936c574a5ce6b56b823b", "question": "What was Queen Victoria's first name?", "answer": "Alexandrina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf99", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, which two letters have the highest values?", "answer": "Q and Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989acb0cb8751d53e7d760c", "question": "Which two twin primes add up to 360?", "answer": "179 and 181", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ea", "question": "What is the fin on the back of a whale called?", "answer": "Dorsal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e6bd06d333868d34d735", "question": "In the Bible, who was Abraham's first son?", "answer": "Ishmael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"luau\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be581a05415ba52ed6f0ac3", "question": "Who released an autobiography titled \"Making Waves: The Autobiography\"?", "answer": "David Hasselhoff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b85b", "question": "What spirit is mixed with ginger beer and lime to make a Moscow Mule?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067fa2ff9c0647b50a8086", "question": "What years did Nancy Reagan serve as the First of the United States?", "answer": "1981 to 1989", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c84", "question": "Who wrote the play \"A Streetcar Named Desire\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60121b2963c99d48cd169b0c", "question": "A soniferous object produces what?", "answer": "Sound -- Soniferous animals don\u2019t just make sound, it\u2019s an especially loud and far-reaching sound.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23d", "question": "What does an Apiarist do?", "answer": "Keeps bees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a728c336bcd28c119383282", "question": "What is the name of Christopher Lee's autobiography?", "answer": "Tall, Dark and Gruesome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59220151a4edfd43a087adda", "question": "Whose autobiography is titled \"Dreams From My Father\"?", "answer": "Barack Obama's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e6e606d333868d34d737", "question": "The \"September Massacres\" refers to the slaughter of political prisoners in what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bb96364247bf200fb8a5", "question": "What is a Karahi?", "answer": "A wok-like cooking pot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2c", "question": "The title for the novel \"A Brave New World\" was derived from which Shakespearean play?", "answer": "The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a382", "question": "What is the capital of the Netherlands?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d3", "question": "Which New England state does not have any ocean coastline?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be28", "question": "What world's currency is the Linden dollar?", "answer": "Second Life", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f167cdf7c52aae91cc07be", "question": "The Bijagos Archipelago lie off which country's mainland?", "answer": "Guinea-Bissau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be26", "question": "What bird did Ben Franklin suggest replace the bald eagle as a national emblem?", "answer": "The wild turkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5da856251aec824685d88d05", "question": "What continent is Morocco located in?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a957561d1b4d384d5d67a", "question": "Who, or what, was the \"First Reich\"?", "answer": "The Holy Roman Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab3", "question": "What were Donner and Blitzen's names in the 1823 publication of, A Visit from St. Nicholas", "answer": "Dunder and Blixen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4bf", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Mauritania and Guinea-Bissau?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cd", "question": "What is the more common term for sternum?", "answer": "Breastbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c012", "question": "What did a Cordwainer make?", "answer": "Shoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b40d06d333868d34d6df", "question": "What part of the world did the Vikings come from?", "answer": "Scandinavia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59637204967692ea851899bc", "question": "Ford produced the Model T in only what color after 1913?", "answer": "Black", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab0c04baab681b09292167", "question": "What 2005 horror short film shares a name with a piece of jewelry?", "answer": "Rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba4c4874c93a3298b2148", "question": "What is the highest mountain in Wales?", "answer": "Mount Snowdon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600243894be4723ccac22198", "question": "What was the name of the first book in Laura Ingalls Wilder\u2019s \"Little House\" series?", "answer": "\"Little House in the Big Woods\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a162a64f01ec323f8491723", "question": "What carries sensations from the tongue to the brain?", "answer": "Lingual nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937eb5b08d98002fdd633ad", "question": "Which three family members released an album titled \"Priority\" in 1979?", "answer": "The Pointer Sisters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acea", "question": "Which president's wife helped fund the war effort by auctioning wool from sheep grazing on the White House lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c82c", "question": "Thomas Edison was \"the Wizard of Menlo Park\" in what US state?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a652", "question": "Oregon's Mount Hood is located in what mountain chain?", "answer": "Cascade Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75b", "question": "If you take a road trip to Hawaii, what road signs would you see?", "answer": "You can't drive to Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339501", "question": "What year was the movie \"Titanic\" released?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8b", "question": "Who designed the famous collection of buildings in Oak Park, Illinois?", "answer": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600787f40eee65b76b9f265e", "question": "Which American engineer invented his \"Magic Infallible Bank Lock\" in 1851?", "answer": "Linus Yale, Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb41265ff7d326b622a84", "question": "What year was Budweiser first introduced?", "answer": "1876", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d06d67870e6f05ba600858", "question": "What metals is Bell metal an alloy of?", "answer": "Tin and copper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8d", "question": "What love\u00adstruck Warner Brothers cartoon character often chased a black cat named Penelope?", "answer": "Pepe Le Pew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d98", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Joad?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef62056ce05a3942286e5a", "question": "What was Jimi Hendrix's birth name?", "answer": "Johnny Allen Hendrix", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b148", "question": "Who was the first US President born outside the 13 original states?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln,", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae866977f28483af1e7fdd4", "question": "What is the name of the musician best known for his 1993 song \"What is Love\"?", "answer": "Haddaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339617", "question": "Adam West portrayed which superhero on television?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a43c9d816e292245c16", "question": "What American artist is known for paintings of flags?", "answer": "Jasper Johns is an American painter, sculptor and printmaker associated with Abstract expressionism, Neo-Dada, and Pop art.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f95a9e555722f97b22684d1", "question": "What was the last movie Walt Disney was able to work on before he died?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4f", "question": "Little Red Riding Hood was called what in the original story by the Brothers Grimm?", "answer": "Little Red Cap", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c996", "question": "Heroin is the brand name of morphine once marketed by which pharmaceutical company?", "answer": "Bayer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e94e17ccba3ffe45786d9", "question": "What language was the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "FLOW-MATIC", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c720", "question": "What part of the human body experiences different growth rates called anagen, catagen, and telogen?", "answer": "The hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002414f4be4723ccac22175", "question": "Who was the leader of the wolves in \"The Jungle Book\"?", "answer": "Akala", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72b", "question": "The Ohio River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e96747ccba3ffe45786ee", "question": "In which European country would you find the Tokaj wine region?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b9", "question": "Inclusive of macrons, the original Hawaiian alphabet has how many letters?", "answer": "17", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c743", "question": "What is the more common term for amblyopia?", "answer": "Lazy eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe2", "question": "What is the Latin word for poison?", "answer": "Virus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d116fb4fea7fe947a22275", "question": "Mickey Mouse is known as what in Italy?", "answer": "Topolino", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd7feec223966ae8f88da", "question": "Where was singer Billy Ocean born?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925f", "question": "What band turned down an offer from \"Gap\" to use their song \"Don't Panic\"?", "answer": "Coldplay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008da4cf4f3bc4a292f8614", "question": "Where was the first commercial winery in the U.S.?", "answer": "Kentucky (Swiss vintner, John James Dufour, chose a spot along the Kentucky River for his vineyards and opened a winery in 1799.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f1781e4b8195c09b948d5c2", "question": "Which abolitionist wrote the newspapers called \"The Liberator\"?", "answer": "William Lloyd Garrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b892", "question": "What is the highest score in darts from three different doubles?", "answer": "114", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a97c261d1b4d384d5d688", "question": "Which impresionist artist's most important work was his series of paintings based around Hampton on the river Thames?", "answer": "Alfred Sisley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c284", "question": "How would you write 99 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "XCIX", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a60b", "question": "To which South American country to the Galapagos Islands belong?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ea40fe83fe1f2a824bef", "question": "In 2007, purported remains of what saint were found to be from an Egyptian mummy instead?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0adfee662d71a53650fb6", "question": "To raise money for charities, who handwrote an 800-word prequel to her bestselling book series?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914f", "question": "Who was the Greek god of volcanoes?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339635", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Jasmine?", "answer": "Aladdin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dd6df4f3bc4a292f8621", "question": "Who was president the first time the U.S. Congress voted to declare war?", "answer": "James Madison (On 1 June 1812, he sent a message to Congress recounting U.S. grievances against Great Britain.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971c", "question": "In \"The Addams Family\", what does Morticia do that always excites Gomez?", "answer": "Speaks French", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3f1", "question": "What is a dromophobiac afraid to cross?", "answer": "A street", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2e", "question": "India became an independent country in what year?", "answer": "1947", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942f", "question": "Who directed the 1989 movie \"Dead Poets Society\"?", "answer": "Peter Weir", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339816", "question": "Whose first album was titled \"The Divine Miss M\"?", "answer": "Bette Midler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c204", "question": "What year did the US host their first Olympic Games?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121ac663c99d48cd169b08", "question": "What is the main ingredient of Bombay Duck?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa5446ce05a3942286ebc", "question": "In the film \"Airplane!\", what was the name of Leslie Nelson's character?", "answer": "Dr. Alan Rumack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062bfac9d816e292245c27", "question": "What artist is best known for a painting of his mother?", "answer": "James McNeil Whistler's most famous painting is \"Arrangement in Black and Grey No.1\".  It is commonly known \"Whistler's Mother\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d8", "question": "What pro sport did Althea Gibson play when her tennis career ended?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a182", "question": "Turbo Terrific is a car featured in which cartoon?", "answer": "Wacky Races", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb69d05dad637d903c884a", "question": "What US state has a diamond illustrated on its license plate?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ee", "question": "Which play was originally titled \"Mistakes of a Night\"?", "answer": "She Stoops to Conquer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85a", "question": "What disease grounded astronaut Ken Mattingly from Apollo 13?", "answer": "The measles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d8", "question": "Who was the last British monarch to also be an emperor?", "answer": "George VI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b8", "question": "In 2005, Bhutan became the first country to entirely ban what?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c410877e98cb9777899a", "question": "What city requires aspiring cab drivers to undergo years of training?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b7a7364247bf200fb874", "question": "Who had a hit in 1988 with the song \"I Get Weak\"?", "answer": "Belinda Carlisle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067ce8ff9c0647b50a8071", "question": "What is the name of the sixth expansion to the World of Warcraft game universe?", "answer": "World of Warcraft: Legion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a036", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", what does Quagmire do in an attempt to get out of his marriage?", "answer": "Fake his own death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b1", "question": "In 1975, what re-opened after an 8 year closure?", "answer": "Suez Canal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a9a", "question": "In the children?s nursery rhyme, what comes next after ?Mary, Mary quite contrary??", "answer": "How does your garden grow?", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacf", "question": "Which sports league awards the Larry O'Brien trophy to the team that wins the yearly Championship?", "answer": "NBA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff517fcff04d658268c92fe", "question": "By which nickname is Henry McCarty better known?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf28", "question": "The pound cake got its name from the pound of what ingredient that it contains?", "answer": "Butter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b4", "question": "When did sharpshooter Annie Oakley die?", "answer": "1926", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b187", "question": "Who was US President Ronald Reagan's first wife?", "answer": "Jane Wyman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f3056f75aa2bc17b61b2acd", "question": "The song \"Afternoon Delight\" was the only major hit for which one-hit-wonder group?", "answer": "Starland Vocal Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cae0877e98cb97778a0d", "question": "You can find Grand Teton National Park in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe655a2ae7e414034b5aeb6", "question": "What was Henry Ford\u2019s original design for a car called?", "answer": "Quadricycle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cafa", "question": "Poinephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Punishment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b071", "question": "Which former First Lady co\u00adwrote the Declaration of Human Rights which was adopted by the United Nations?", "answer": "Eleanor Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4a", "question": "What is the last event in a decathlon?", "answer": "1500 Metres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06d", "question": "What dynasty was founded in China in 1368 by Emperor Hong Wu?", "answer": "Ming Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d7", "question": "Which is US's largest state by land area?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb62", "question": "What product used the advertising slogan, \"Where's your moustache?\"", "answer": "Milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae958a574a5ce6b56b8256", "question": "What is the name of the raven in George Orwell's \"Animal Farm\"?", "answer": "Moses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c8a53690aac110e4167072", "question": "What types of beer are usually used in the making of a Black and Tan?", "answer": "Pale lager and stout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c158", "question": "Who was the first thoroughbred horse to win one million dollars?", "answer": "Citation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6dd", "question": "What constellation represents a hunter with a club a shield?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a589", "question": "Which present day US state did Ponce De Leon explore?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b675", "question": "What was William Fox Talbot a pioneer of?", "answer": "Photography", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd5", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"Q\"?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe657daae7e414034b5aee3", "question": "In the Book of Deuteronomy, which mountain is also known as the Mount of Blessing?", "answer": "Mount Gerizim", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339086", "question": "What form of verse is \"Paradise Lost\" written in?", "answer": "Blank verse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a1", "question": "Which staircase in the Leaning Tower of Pisa has fewer steps?", "answer": "The north-facing one", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590721263745b36be73039f5", "question": "Who played the role of Kris Kringle in the 1947 film \"Miracle on 34th Street\"?", "answer": "Edmund Gwenn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feb31db7e83c707845b20c2", "question": "What meteorological phenomenon causes a warm current of water to appear every three to seven years in the eastern Pacific Ocean, causing unusual weather conditions all over the world?", "answer": "El Ni\u00f1o", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a814", "question": "In what county is Chicago, Illinois located?", "answer": "Cook County", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc61", "question": "The name \"denim\" originates from what European language?", "answer": "French", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd50ca00d154d7af00b8d8", "question": "Scott Raynor is the original drummer of which rock band?", "answer": "Blink-182", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339892", "question": "Who did Johnny Carson replace as host of \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Jack Paar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a390", "question": "Where in London are the Crown Jewels kept?", "answer": "The Tower of London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e3", "question": "Which Scientologist was trapped in the closet in the \"Trapped in the Closet\" episode of South Park?", "answer": "Tom Cruise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e2", "question": "In which Chinese city is the Terracotta Army?", "answer": "Xian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964a", "question": "What planet is home to the Jedi Temple?", "answer": "Coruscant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b23ae328f1a2238a7cb2b3b", "question": "What is the southernmost continent?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac9", "question": "Which two books of the New Testament have names that begin with letter \"R\"?", "answer": "Romans and Revelation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b13", "question": "Who did Lionel Richie duet with on the 1981 #1 smash \"Endless Love\"?", "answer": "Diana Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a596", "question": "What is the geographical term for a ring-shaped coral island?", "answer": "Atoll", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a998d61d1b4d384d5d69c", "question": "What year did the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" end its 20 season run?", "answer": "1975", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb24765ff7d326b622a73", "question": "Oysters wrapped in bacon are commonly referred to as what?", "answer": "Angels on Horseback", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba4d8874c93a3298b2149", "question": "What is the Welsh name for Mount Snowdon?", "answer": "Yr Wyddfa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a766", "question": "In which US state is Oral Roberts University located?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa3", "question": "Which British telephone number first came into use in 1937?", "answer": "999", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339845", "question": "Julie Andrews won an Oscar for her role in what Disney classic?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a973861d1b4d384d5d681", "question": "What is the more common name for a \"travelator\"?", "answer": "Moving walkway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c0", "question": "What is the more common name for Scapula?", "answer": "Shoulder blade", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888c", "question": "Who wrote \"A Farewell to Arms\"?", "answer": "Earnest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdb56ec223966ae8f88f3", "question": "In \"Die Hard,\" how does John McClane signal officer Powell that something is wrong at Nakatomi Plaza?", "answer": "Drops a dead body on his car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2e", "question": "What university did David Letterman graduate from in 1969 with a degree in telecommunications?", "answer": "Ball State", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb74", "question": "An amendment to the US Constitution must be ratified by what fraction of all the states?", "answer": "75%", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c4", "question": "What is the technical term for egg white?", "answer": "Albumen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90d0fa52800b05cac20f10", "question": "What is Eisoptrophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Mirrors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59c1cdfe7bd84c0ea43ad432", "question": "Which city is directly northwest of Windsor, Ontario?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abd", "question": "Which art form derives its name from the Greek for \"beauty writing\"?", "answer": "Calligraphy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8d", "question": "Francis Scott Key wrote what famous song?", "answer": "The Star Spangled Banner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf0", "question": "What is the literal translation of the word \"tofu\"?", "answer": "Bean curd", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is Smithers' first name?", "answer": "Waylon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66b3a52a821ff76ae8b0d", "question": "Which Old West figure became sports editor for the \"New York Morning Telegraph\"?", "answer": "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071dcc3745b36be73039dd", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a6", "question": "What is the literal translation of the word Brandy?", "answer": "Burned wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac66", "question": "Which incident is said to have started World War II?", "answer": "Poland's invasion by Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571c0e67df192a942e3370", "question": "What year did Anthony Burgess publish his dystopian novel, \"A Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "1962", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05f", "question": "What famous Cherokee Indian created the alphabet for the Cherokee language?", "answer": "Sequoyah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb3216e368446ca7bd6840", "question": "Which element has the lowest boiling point?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b479e662d71a53650feb", "question": "Why did Michelangelo dislike Raphael?", "answer": "He thought Raphael was copying him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e4", "question": "St. Louis' Gateway Arch is officially named for what US president?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590678ebff9c0647b50a804e", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59da1bc3f6756c9b30ba14fd", "question": "Graham Kerr became famous under what nickname?", "answer": "The Galloping Gourmet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd65", "question": "What's sometimes called a \"licking stick\" or a \"tin sandwich\"?", "answer": "A harmonica", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015dfe5fe83fe1f2a824b83", "question": "What year was the fire extinguisher invented?", "answer": "1723", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b0", "question": "What phenomenon is named for the French words for \"already seen\"?", "answer": "Deja vu", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0bf", "question": "What is the fear of progress known as?", "answer": "Prosophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a3126c0f9723ab15cb49", "question": "What was the first department store?", "answer": "Harding, Howell and Company Grand Fashionable Magazine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c496877e98cb977789a1", "question": "In which Canadian province do the Appalachian Mountains end?", "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ec2f06d333868d34d761", "question": "In which year was the White Australia Policy formally abolished?", "answer": "1972", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab23", "question": "Which ocean does Mozambique has water access to?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973e", "question": "What was Fonzie's fill name on the TV show \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Arthur Herbert Fonzarelli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a7cf20565ad31a57c7ef", "question": "What was the first US state to pass a law requiring mandatory seat belt use?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9c", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Caballerial\"?", "answer": "Skateboarding", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd9de7e83c707845b217e", "question": "In the game of golf, the iconic \"Green Jacket\" is presented to the winner of which championship?", "answer": "Masters Tournament", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65973ae7e414034b5aeff", "question": "What was the first European country to allow women to vote?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaaa47e83c707845b20e0", "question": "Alektorophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Chickens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29e", "question": "What sports event did Rosie Ruiz win by cheating in 1980?", "answer": "The Boston Marathon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339295", "question": "On what book series is the HBO TV series \"True Blood\" based?", "answer": "The Southern Vampire Mysteries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c808", "question": "What popular aquarium fish is known as pla-kad in its native Thailand?", "answer": "The Siamese fighting fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd76", "question": "What part of a pig is eaten as \"chitterlings\"?", "answer": "The intestines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25f2426682715b82711ce9", "question": "Feijoada, the national dish of Brazil, originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af0", "question": "What type of animal is Napoleon, in George Orwell\u2019s novel \u201cAnimal Farm?\u201d", "answer": "A pig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597742ce284458f1d7854422", "question": "What two Coaches on \"The Voice\" US have been on from season 1 through season 14?", "answer": "Blake Shelton and Adam Levine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071d2c3745b36be73039d5", "question": "What Soviet operation forced over 2,000 scientists and engineers to relocate from East Germany to Russia to work on missile design and production?", "answer": "Operation Osoaviakhim", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b923", "question": "What car company was named for the founder of Detroit?", "answer": "Cadillac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a323", "question": "Who had a hit in 1994 with the song \"Shakermaker\"?", "answer": "Oasis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb2af65ff7d326b622a77", "question": "Mycophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Mushrooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a3", "question": "What mountain chain extends from western Canada down through Northern California?", "answer": "The Cascades", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af19", "question": "What did the Pony Express transport to California?", "answer": "Mail", "category": "history"}]